<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<qXML>
<!--frame>
<question>
    <index></index>
    <clinical>
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage></qImage>
    <mainQ>
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a></a>
        <b></b>
        <c></c>
        <d></d>
        <e></e>
        </choices>
    <answer></answer>
    <exp>
        </exp>
    <aImage>
        </aImage>
    <ref></ref>
</question-->

<!--1 nsvt-->
<question>
    <index>Tx Withheld</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/NSVT.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Why did ICD withhold the therapy?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>The ventricular rate was not fast enough.</a>
        <b>The arrhythmia was not properly sensed.</b>
        <c>The arrhythmia interval was too irregular.</c>
        <d>The arrhythmia was supraventricular in origin.</d>
        <e>The duration of the arrhythmia was too short.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>E</answer>
    <exp>The arrhythmia was wide complex tachycardia. The rate was fast enough to fall into the VT and VF detection zone; labelled as TS and TF respectively. Every beat was sensed correctly. However, the duration was not sustained enough to trigger the therapy.
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--2 vf shock-->
<question>
    <index>ICD Shock</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/vfShock.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following is correct?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Lead noise was present.</a>
        <b>The therapy was appropriate.</b>
        <c>The therapy was unnecessary.</c>
        <d>The therapy was unsucessful.</d>
        <e>Electromagnetic interference was detected.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>B</answer>
    <exp>The tracing was ventricular fibrillation and the therapy was necessary and appropriate.
    There were some VF beats that were not sensed. All undersensed beats were small in amplitude and occurred after a beat with a much larger amplitude.
    Lead noise should not be seen in far-field EGM. Also, in the near-field EGM of a lead noise case, the amplitude will likely be high and saturate the channel.
    Noted with some definitions: Inappropriate therapy = therapy for non-VT/VF; Unnecessary therapy = therapy for VT/VF that could have been avoided.

        </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--3 ICD Coil-->
<question>
    <index>ICD Coil</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the benefit of a single-coil ICD lead over a dual-coil ICD lead?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>A single-coil lead provide a better sensing profile.</a>
        <b>A single-coil lead has a smaller diameter.</b>
        <c>A single-coil lead provide a lower defibrillation threshold.</c>
        <d>A single-coil lead is associated with lower complication during an implantation.</d>
        <e>A single-coil lead is associated with lower complication during the extraction.</e>
    </choices>
    <answer>E</answer>
    <exp>Because of the abundance of data showing no benefit of dual-coil over single-coil leads and a higher associated complication rate during lead extraction, Single-coil leads should be regarded as the standard of care for ICDs. 
    Dual-coil leads might be considered in populations in which the dft threshold might be higher and/or when dft safety margin fails with a single-coil lead.
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjca.2016.09.009</ref>
</question>

<!--4 dual over single-->
<question>
    <index>Dual over Single ICD</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the benefit of a dual-chamber ICD over a single-chamber ICD?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Reduce incidence of AF in patients wtih sick sinus syndrome.</a>
        <b>Reduce complication during implantation.</b>
        <c>Reduce incidence of inappropriate shock.</c>
        <d>Lower defibrillation threshold</d>
        <e>Lower battery consumption.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>A</answer>
    <exp>An RCT of patients without bradycardia pacing indication showed no difference in the incidence of inappropriate shock between dual-chamber and single-chamber ICD.
    A dual-chamber is always associated with a more complications during implantation and a more battery consumption than a single-chamber device.
    Dual-chamber ICD should be considered over single-chamber ICD in patients with sinus node dysfunction or AV block with preserved LV function.
        </exp>
    <aImage>media/singleVsDual.png</aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euu022</ref>
</question>

<!--#5 integrated bipolar lead-->
<question>
    <index>sensing issue</index>
    <clinical>A 45 y/o man with non-ischemic cardiomyopathy underwent single chamber ICD implantation 6 weeks ago. During his first follow-up device evaluation, several tachycardia episodes are noted in the tracing shown.
    </clinical>
    <qImage>media/iBipolar.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following is the next best step?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Increase sensitivity value and perform DFTs.</a>
        <b>PVC ablation.</b>
        <c>Reposition RV lead.</c>
        <d>Extend PVAB interval.</d>
        <e>Continue to follow clinically.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>C</answer>
    <exp>The recordings show a consistently spaced interval between two signals with the initial signal lower amplitude than the second signal.
    This suggests an INTEGRATED BIPOLAR LEAD with atrial sensing; the newly implanted ICD lead is probably too shallow in the RV. This problem cannot be overcome by programming changes.
    If left uncorrected, oversensing atrial signal could potentially lead to inappropriate therapy.
    Ref: 2016 Self-Assessment and Exam Prep in Clinical Cardiac Electrophysiology. Heart Rhythm Society.</exp>
    <aImage>media/trueVsIntegrated.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>

</question>

<!--#6 high DFT-->
<question>
    <index>CXR</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/highDFT.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Findings on the CXR are most consistent with which of the following?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Biventricular pacing.</a>
        <b>High defibrillation threshold.</b>
        <c>Lead-induced subcutaneous emphyhsema.</c>
        <d>Right ventricular outflow tract pacing.</d>
        <e>Situs inversus.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>B</answer>
    <exp>CXR showed a high-voltage coil placed in the axililary area because of high DFTs.
    Ref: IBHRE Examination Prep
        </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#7 TWOS shock-->
<question>
    <index>After Shock</index>
    <clinical>Recordings are shown from ICD interrogation showing events leading to ICD shock which the patient received shortly after beginning to walk on a treadmill for exercise. 
    </clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/TWOS1.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>
        What is the most appropriate strategy to prevent additional ICD shocks?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Catheter ablation of ventricular tachycardia.</a>
        <b>Administer beta blocker to prevent sinus tachycardia.</b>
        <c>Replace fractured lead.</c>
        <d>Raise the sensitivity threshold.</d>
        <e>Turn on ATP during charging.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D
        </answer>
    <exp>The tachogram showed 2 constant cycle lengths, alternating between 320 and 260ms intervals producing the train track appearance of the sensed activity. This train track pattern occurred when the heart rate exceeded 100 bpm.
    Without looking at the episode tracing, this highly likely represents a T-wave oversensing.
    The tracing confirmed the oversensing of T wave. Raising the sensitivity threshold is the initial managment.
    When sensitivity settings are raised to avoid T wave oversensing, testing for VF detection should be considered.
    Ref: 2016 Self-Assessment and Exam Prep in Clinical Cardiac Electrophysiology. Heart Rhythm Society.
    </exp>
    <aImage>media/TWOS1Ans.png</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#8 VF sesning-->
<question>
    <index>VF Sensing</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following ICD features are designed to ensure appropriate ventricular arrhythmia sensing?
    </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Auto-adjusting PVARP</a>
        <b>Auto-adjusting Ventricular Sensing Threshold</b>
        <c>High value (more than 0.6mV) of Ventricular Sensitivity</c>
        <d>Long (more than 30ms) cross-chamber blanking period after paced events</d>
        <e>Long (more than 30ms) cross-chamber blanking period after sensed events</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>B</answer>
    <exp>To provide appropriate sensing, the ICD uses:
    - Auto-adjusting atrial and ventricular sensing thresholds.
    - Short (30ms) cross-chamber blanking after paced events.
    - No cross-chamber blanking after sensed events.
    Ventricular sensitivity of 0.3 mV is recommended to maximize the probability that VF will be detected. A value greater than 0.6mV is not recommended except for testing.
    Ref: GEM DR System Reference Guide, Medtronic.
        </exp>
    <aImage>media/autoSense.png</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#9 1st shock success-->
<question>
    <index>Shock Success Rate</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the success rate of the first ICD shock to terminate ventricular arrhythmia when using maximum energy?
    </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>90-100%</a>
        <b>80-90%</b>
        <c>60-70%</c>
        <d>50%</d>
        <e>25-50%</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>B</answer>
    <exp>The success rate of first shock as first therapy is approximately 90%. The success rate reaches 100% by 2nd and 3rd shocks.
    The success rate of 1st shock was lower after failed ATP (85%). 
    </exp>
    <aImage>media/1Shock.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2013.01.019</ref>
</question>

<!--#10 shock efficacy-->
<question>
    <index>Shock Efficacy</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following factors improves the efficacy of ICD shock?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Using monophasic shock.</a>
        <b>Lowering the ventricular sensitivity number.</b>
        <c>Positioning the RV coil as apically as possible.</c>
        <d>Programming longer duration for detection.</d>
        <e>Using the shock energy at the upper limit of vulnerability.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>C</answer>
    <exp>Biphasic defibrillation is more effective at lower energy levels compared to monophasic defibrillation.
    A more proximal location of RV coil was associated with an increase in DFT.
    Other stratgies to improve the efficacy of ICD shock are reverse shock polarity, remove SVC coil if shock impedance is less than 40 ohms, using high output device, and etc.
    Energy at the upper limit of vulnerability is approximately the defibrillation threshold. 
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2005.12.023</ref>
</question>

<!--#11 a dislodge after DFT-->
<question>
    <index>After DFT</index>
    <clinical>The above tracing was recorded after a DFT testing during an initial implantation.</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/ADislodge.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the next best appropriate thing to do?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Repeat the DFT testing with a different shock vector.</a>
        <b>Repeat the DFT testing with a higher shock energy.</b>
        <c>Reposition the RV lead.</c>
        <d>Reposition the RA lead.</d>
        <e>Nothing further.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>The tracing showed VF that was induced by ventricular pacing. 
    VF was sensed and shock was delivered. The shock successfully terminated the VF.
    However, after the shock, A lead fell into the ventricular. The A signal was sensed at the same time as the V signal.
    Therefore, A lead repositioning is required.
        </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#12 AF VT-->
<question>
    <index>ATP</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/AFVT.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is correct about this tracing?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>The therapy was unnecessary.</a>
        <b>The therapy was not successful.</b>
        <c>The arrhtyhmia was misclassified.</c>
        <d>The arrhythmia was not correctly sensed.</d>
        <e>At least one of the arrhythmia was terminated.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>E</answer>
    <exp>The top part of the tracing showed AF with biventricular pacing.
    The bottom part showed AF with ventricular tachycardia. Noted that the ventricular EGM became faster and more regular.
    The device correctly identified the arrhythmia as VF+SVT. ATP was successfully terminated the VT but not AF.
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#13 lead Fx-->
<question>
    <index>Shock Trigger</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/leadFx.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>What triggered the ICD shock?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Lead noises.</a>
        <b>Ventricular arrhythmia.</b>
        <c>There was no ICD shock.</c>
        <d>Electromagnetic interference.</d>
        <e>AF with rapid ventricular resposne.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>A</answer>
    <exp>Lead noises were evident in the near-field EGM. Further interrogation is as shown.
    Lead fracture is the cause of the inappropriate shock.
    </exp>
    <aImage>media/fidelis.png</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#14 ATP in fVT-->
<question>
    <index>ATP in FVT</index>
    <clinical>The tracing was obtained from a 62 year-old man with ischemic cardiomyopathy during a routine ICD follow-up visit. The patient complained of some vague symptoms at the time of the event. He did not pass out or develop any heart failure symptoms.</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/ATPinFVT.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>What would be the most appropriate management?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Turn off ATP therapy for VT faster than 360ms.</a>
        <b>Initiate antiarrhythmia therapy.</b>
        <c>Turn on SVT discrimination.</c>
        <d>Reposition the RV lead.</d>
        <e>Upgrade to a CRT-D.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>C</answer>
    <exp>The tracing showed a successful ATP therapy in a fast monomorphic VT. No further device adjustment is needed.
    The detail of the episode is as shown. Wavelet measurement showed no match. 
    On the clinical side, medication initiation and adjustment is needed to reduce the further episodes.
    </exp>
    <aImage>media/ATPinFVTAns.png</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#15 reconfirm shock-->
<question>
    <index>Shock Withheld</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/reconfirmShock.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Why was the ICD shock withheld?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>The rate was too slow.</a>
        <b>The shock was actually delivered.</b>
        <c>The ICD failed to reconfirm the ventricular arrhythmia.</c>
        <d>The arrhythmia was supraventricular in origin.</d>
        <e>The ATP has successfully terminated the tachycardia.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>C</answer>
    <exp>The tracing showed a rapid ventricular tachycardia that self terminated before the ICD shock delivered.
    In a modern ICD, before the device delivers the 1st defibrillation shock for a VF episode, it monitors the cardiac rhythm to confirm that the VF remains present.
    Ref: Medtronic Consulta CRT-D Clinican Manual
    </exp>
    <aImage>media/reconfirmShockAns.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#16 TWOS small R wave-->
<question>
    <index>ICD Shock</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/TWOS2.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following is correct regarding the above tracing?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>R wave amplitude was small.</a>
        <b>The therapy was necessary.</b>
        <c>ATP could have prevented the shock.</c>
        <d>The therapy was unsuccessful.</d>
        <e>Electromagnetic interference triggered the ICD therapy.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>A</answer>
    <exp>The tracing showed T-wave oversensing causing an inappropriate shock.
    R wave, as measured in the Vtip-Vring EGM, was 2-3 mV. The small R wave likely contributed to the oversensing.
    The initial management in this case is to adjust the ventricular sensitivity to a higher number. Should that deem unsafe and unfeasible, RV lead reposition might be required.
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#17 FFRW Bigem-->
<question>
    <index>non-sustained tachy</index>
    <clinical>A 74 y/o woman with an ischemic cardiomyopathy and DDD ICD has the tracing shown recorded in clinic.</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/FFRW.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>What does the tracing show?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Ventricular bigeminy and atrial flutter</a>
        <b>Atrial bigeminy with conduction of atrial extrasystole</b>
        <c>Ventricular bigeminy and far field R wave oversensing</c>
        <d>Atrial tachycardia with rapid ventricular response</d>
        <e>Bidirectional ventricular tachycardia</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>C</answer>
    <exp>The rhythm was presumed sinus rhythm (AS-VS) with bigeminy PVCs. The A channel recorded far-field V signals both regular beats and PVCs.
    Ref: 2016 Self-Assessment and Exam Prep in Clinical Cardiac Electrophysiology. Heart Rhythm Society.</exp>
    <aImage>media/FFRWAns.png</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

<!--#18 ATP success rate-->
<question>
    <index>ATP success rate</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the success rate of ATP in termination of ventricular tachycardia in a patient with ischemic cardiomyopathy?</mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>close to 100%</a>
        <b>more than 80%</b>
        <c>50-70%</c>
        <d>less than 50%</d>
        <e>Likely unsuccessful</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>B</answer>
    <exp>In patients with structural heart disease, the efficacy of ATP for VT slower than 188 bpm is close to 90%, and the effecity for VT rate 188-220 bpm is 76%.
    ATP therapy is recommended in all ventricular tachyarrhythmia detection zone. The recommended ATP programming is to deliver at least 1 ATP attempt with a minimum of 8 stimuli and a cycle length of 84%-88% of the tachycardia cycle length.
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euv411</ref>
</question>

<!--#19 unnecessary shock-->
<question>
    <index>unnecessary Shock</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>How should an ICD be programmed to minimize unnecessary ICD shock?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Maximum energy for all shocks.</a>
        <b>ATP during charging in a patient with Brugada syndrome.</b>
        <c>VF detection at 150 bpm in an ICD implanted for primary prophylaxis.</c>
        <d>Minimum energy for the 1st shock and escalating energy for the follwoing shocks.</d>
        <e>ATP in VT zone only if ICD was implanted for primary prevension.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>A</answer>
    <exp>Maximum first shock energy is associated with higher chance of shock success when compared to lower energy.
    In ICD for primary prevention, VF detection should be programmed to require the tachycardia to continue at least 30 beats at the rate between 185-200 bpm to reduce unnecessary therapy.
    </exp>
    <aImage>NA</aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euv411</ref>
</question>

<!--#20 wavelets-->
<question>
    <index>No therapy</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
           
    <qImage>media/wavelet.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Why did not the ICD deliver the therapy?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>The rate was too slow.</a>
        <b>The duration of the arrhythmia was to short.</b>
        <c>The arrhythmia was not correctly sensed.</c>
        <d>The arrhythmia was determined to be supraventricular in origin.</d>
        <e>The detection duration reached time out.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>The tracing showed irregular narrow complex tachycardia, likely atrial fibrillation
    The detail of the episode is shown below. The wavellets matched the native QRS and suggested supraventricular rather than ventricular tachycardia. The therapy was appropriately withheld.
    </exp>
    <aImage>media/waveletAns.png</aImage>
    <ref>NA</ref>
</question>

</qXML>