<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<qXML>
<!--frame>
<question>
    <index></index>
    <clinical>
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage></qImage>
    <mainQ>
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a></a>
        <b></b>
        <c></c>
        <d></d>
        <e></e>
        </choices>
    <answer></answer>
    <exp>
        </exp>
    <aImage>
        </aImage>
    <ref></ref>
</question-->

<!--cause-->
<question>
    <index>Etiologies</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
    
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the most common cause of sudden cardiac death in a 40 year-old man?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Valvular Heart Disease</a>
        <b>Brugada Syndrome</b>
        <c>Commotio Cordis</c>
        <d>Coronary Artery Disease</d>
        <e>Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>CAD is a major cause of SCD in patients aged over 35. In the youngs, 40% of SCDs remained unexplained.
        </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q1_cause.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/imj.14359</ref>
</question>

<!--ICD in stable CAD-->
<question>
    <index>Stable CAD</index>
    <clinical>A 61-year-old woman is admitted to the hospital following a cardiac arrest. She suddenly collapsed and lost consciousness while walking through the airport. An automatic external defibrillator (AED) was applied and after ventricular fibrillation (VF) was demonstrated, she was converted to sinus rhythm with a single shock. 
    She is currently awake and alert. She has no significant prior medical history and uses no medications. Serum electrolytes and cardiac markers were normal in the emergency department. 
    An ECG after resuscitation showed nonspecific repolarization abnormalities. An echocardiogram revealed diffuse global hypokinesis with an LV ejection fraction (EF) of 44%. 
    Cardiac catheterization showed a total occlusion of right coronary artery (RCA) with collaterals.</clinical>
    
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following should you recommend?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Initiation of Amiodarone</a>
        <b>PCI of RCA</b>
        <c>Genetic Testing for Cardiac Channel Mutation</c>
        <d>Implantation of ICD</d>
        <e>Train Family Member to Use AED</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>Sudden cardiac arrest in this patient was likely caused by scar related ventricular arrhythmias from prior MI. Patient had no evidence of acute ischemia by cardiac markers and coronary angiogram. ICD is therefore recommended.
    In CASH trial (Kuck et al. Circulation 2000.), an RCT in survivors of SCA, ICD reduced SCD and all-cause mortality when compared to amiodarone or metoprolol. In this trial, patients with reversible causes of SCA including acute MI were excluded. CAD was recorded in more than 70% of the patients. Mean LVEF was 46%.
    In the current guidelines from all societies, ICD is recommended for a survivor of SCA not from reversible causes. Also, ICD is recommended in a survivor of SCA in stable CAD regardless of LVEF.
    </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q2_stableCAD.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>http://www.onlinejacc.org/content/61/12/1318</ref>
</question>

<!--ICD in early MI-->
<question>
    <index>Early MI</index>
    <clinical>A 45 year-old physician was admitted to CCU 3 days ago with cardiac arrest and acute massive anterior wall MI. He was successfully resuscitated and underwent a PCI of proximal LAD. Echocardiogram done 1 day after the PCI revealed severe LV dysfunction with LVEF 20-25%. During the admission, the telemetry showed no ventricular arrhythmias. 
    The patient recovers very well and would like to go home today. His current medical regimen includes ASA 81 mg OD, Ticagrelor 90 mg BID, Atorvastatin 40 mg OD, Carvedilol 6.25 mg BID, Enalapril 5 mg OD, and Omeprazole 20 mg OD.
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the next appropriate management?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Perform an exercise stress test using submaximal protocol prior to discharge.</a>
        <b>Offer an implantable defibrillator-cardioverter.</b>
        <c>Offer an electrophysiogic study to stratify risk of sudden cardiac death.</c>
        <d>Initiate Amiodarone.</d>
        <e>Repeat an echocardiogram in 4-6 weeks.</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>E</answer>
    <exp>Even though the risk of SCD is highest during the first 30 days after MI, ICD implantation has never been shown to improve mortality. The reason is likely that
        </exp>
    <aImage>
        </aImage>
    <ref></ref>
</question>


</qXML>