<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<qXML>
<!--frame>
<question>
    <index></index>
    <clinical>
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage></qImage>
    <mainQ>
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a></a>
        <b></b>
        <c></c>
        <d></d>
        <e></e>
        </choices>
    <answer></answer>
    <exp>
        </exp>
    <aImage>
        </aImage>
    <ref></ref>
</question-->

<!--cause-->
<question>
    <index>Etiologies</index>
    <clinical>NA</clinical>
    
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>What is the most common cause of sudden cardiac death in a 40 year-old man?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Valvular Heart Disease</a>
        <b>Brugada Syndrome</b>
        <c>Commotio Cordis</c>
        <d>Coronary Artery Disease</d>
        <e>Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>CAD is a major cause of SCD in patients aged over 35. In the youngs, 40% of SCDs remained unexplained.
        </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q1_cause.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/imj.14359</ref>
</question>

<!--ICD in stable CAD-->
<question>
    <index>Stable CAD</index>
    <clinical>A 61-year-old woman is admitted to the hospital following a cardiac arrest. She suddenly collapsed and lost consciousness while walking through the airport. An automatic external defibrillator (AED) was applied and after ventricular fibrillation (VF) was demonstrated, she was converted to sinus rhythm with a single shock. 
    She is currently awake and alert. She has no significant prior medical history and uses no medications. Serum electrolytes and cardiac markers were normal in the emergency department. 
    An ECG after resuscitation showed nonspecific repolarization abnormalities. An echocardiogram revealed diffuse global hypokinesis with an LV ejection fraction (EF) of 44%. 
    Cardiac catheterization showed a total occlusion of right coronary artery (RCA) with collaterals.</clinical>
    
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following should you recommend?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Initiation of Amiodarone</a>
        <b>PCI of RCA</b>
        <c>Genetic Testing for Cardiac Channel Mutation</c>
        <d>Implantation of ICD</d>
        <e>Train Family Member to Use AED</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>Sudden cardiac arrest in this patient was likely caused by scar related ventricular arrhythmias from prior MI. Patient had no evidence of acute ischemia by cardiac markers and coronary angiogram. ICD is therefore recommended.
    In CASH trial (Kuck et al. Circulation 2000.), an RCT in survivors of SCA, ICD reduced SCD and all-cause mortality when compared to amiodarone or metoprolol. In this trial, patients with reversible causes of SCA including acute MI were excluded. CAD was recorded in more than 70% of the patients. Mean LVEF was 46%.
    In the current guidelines from all societies, ICD is recommended for a survivor of SCA not from reversible causes. Also, ICD is recommended in a survivor of SCA in stable CAD regardless of LVEF.
    </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q2_stableCAD.png
        </aImage>
    <ref>http://www.onlinejacc.org/content/61/12/1318</ref>
</question>

<!--Q4 Syncope in post MI-->
<question>
    <index>Syncope</index>
    <clinical>A 75 year-old man with prior history of myocardial infarction comes in for a routine follow up. He denies any chest pain or changes in functional class. His wife, however, tells you that he passed out twice, one last month and another one last week. The first episode occurred while he was sitting at the dinner table finishing up his dinner. The patient denied any prodromal symptoms. His wife said he suddenly lost his consciousness with his eyes rolled back. He was back to himself within a minute or so. The second episode was similar but occurred while he was sitting in the sofa watching TV.
    His current medications are ASA 81 mg OD, Atorvastatin 40 mg OD, and Enalapril 20 mg OD. 
    Physical examination is unremarkable. ECG is as shown. Echocardiogram reveals LVEF 50% with inferior wall hypokinesis. Coronary angiogram shows total occlusion of RCA with good collaterals. The left-sided coronary system are without significant stenosis.
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage>mediaSCD\Q4_Syncope_ECG.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following should you recommend?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Beta Blocker</a>
        <b>Programmed Ventricular Stimulation</b>
        <c>Transvenous ICD Implantation</c>
        <d>Wearable ICD</d>
        <e>Implantable Loop Recorder</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>B</answer>
    <exp>VAs are an important cause of syncope or near syncope in patients with ischemic heart disease, particularly those with prior infarction.
    EP study has been shown to be able to identify those with high risks for SCD and those whom ICD would be beneficial.
    An ICD is warranted for patients with syncope and inducible sustained monomorphic VT even if they do not otherwise meet criteria for primary prevention.
        </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q4_Syncope_Answer.jpg
        </aImage>
    <ref>https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000549</ref>
</question>

<!--Q5 MADIT-->
<question>
    <index>1 prevention</index>
    <clinical>You are seeing a 45 year-old man with recent myocardial infarction that occurred 2 months ago. He comes in today for a routine visit. He reports of no chest pain or dyspnea on exertion. He resumes his regular exercise including running of 3km/day.
    Current medications are ASA 81 mg OD, Carvedilol 12.5 mg BID, and Lisinopril 5 mg OD. Echocardiogram was performed earlier today and showed LVEF 25-30% with regional wall motion abnormalities.
    </clinical>
           
    <qImage>NA</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following should you recommend?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Exercise stress test to assess his functional class.</a>
        <b>Electrophysiologic study</b>
        <c>Cardiac MRI</c>
        <d>ICD Implantation</d>
        <e>Continue to follow up</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>The patient met class I indication for ICD for primary prevention according to MADIT II trial.
        </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q5_MADIT.jpg
        </aImage>
    <ref>https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa013474</ref>
</question>

<!--Q6 ARVD-->
<question>
    <index>Palpitation</index>
    <clinical>A 42-year-old male presents to the emergency room with palpitations that began while jogging 3 hours ago. The arrhythmia terminated spontaneously after the 12-lead ECG was obtained (left sided of the figure). His mother died suddenly at the age of 38 years. He has no prior history of cardiac symptoms. Physical examination is normal and the sinus rhythm ECG is shown in the right sided of the figure.
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage>mediaSCD\Q6_ARVD.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which one of the following is the most likely cause of the arrhythmia?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Arrhythmogenic RV cardiomyopathy</a>
        <b>Prior silent anterior wall MI</b>
        <c>Idiopathic RVOT VT</c>
        <d>SVT with Aberrancy</d>
        <e>TCA toxicity</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>A</answer>
    <exp>Wide QRS tachycardia at approximately 150 bpm is noted in the left sided of the figure. AV dissociation is present;thus, the morphology is consistent with VT (rendering option D incorrect). The QRS has anLBBB-like configuration in V1 consistent with anRV or septal origin. The frontal plane axis is directed superiorly consistent with an inferior wall origin, which is not consistent with an origin in the RV outflow tract (option C).
    The ECG in sinus rhythm shows inverted twaves in V1-V3, which is the most common ECG finding in arrhythmogenic RV dysplasia.There is no evidence of an old anterior wall infarction to serve as the source of scar-related VT (option B). A family history of sudden death also supports the diagnosis of arrhythmogenic RV cardiomyopathy.
    
    ECG abnormalities in major criteria of ARVC are: 
    1. TWI V1-V3 or beyond in age>14 in the absence of RBBB, 
    2. Epsilon wave (reproducible low amplitude signals between end of QRS complex to onset of the T wave in the right precordial leads (V1 to V3), and
    3. Non-sustained or sustained VT of LBBB morphology	with superior axis (negative or indetermine QRS in II, III, aVF and positive in aVL).
    </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q6_ACM Risk Stratification.png</aImage>
    <ref>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hlc.2018.10.013</ref>
</question>

<!--Q7 TOF-->
<question>
    <index>TOF</index>
    <clinical>A 44 year-old man with a history of tetralogy of Fallot presents to the emergency department with unheralded syncope while walking his dog. At the age of 5 he had undergone a surgical repair for his tetralogy of Fallot with a transannular patch repair. He had previously been well, jogging two times per week without difficulty. On physical examination he had elevated jugular venous waveforms with prominent a and v waves. There was a right parasternal lift. S1 was normal, S2 was widely split. A 3/5 short diastolic decrescendo murmur and a 2/6 systolic ejection murmur were heard at the left upper sternal border. 
    His ECG is as shown. Transthoracic echocardiogram showed mildly impaired LV systolic function, free pulmonic regurgitation and a severely dilated RV with borderline RV systolic function.
        </clinical>
           
    <qImage>mediaSCD\Q7_TOF.png</qImage>
    <mainQ>Which of the following is the most likely reason for the patient's syncope?
        </mainQ>
    <choices>
        <a>Sinus node dysfunction</a>
        <b>Intermittent complete heart block</b>
        <c>Vagally mediated</c>
        <d>Ventricular tachycardia</d>
        <e>Atrial flutter with 1:1 conduction</e>
        </choices>
    <answer>D</answer>
    <exp>This is a classic presentation of ventricular tachycardia in a patient with repaired Tetralogy of Fallot. He has several risk factors, including a QRS >180 msec, severe pulmonary regurgitation and severely dilated RV. He will also need pulmonic valve replacement and likely ablation of his ventricular tachycardia. Although sinus node dysfunction is possible in patients with tetralogy of Fallot, it is not common and would not be anticipated to initially present as syncope. Similarly, though complete heart block could present with syncope, it is uncommon in patients with tetralogy of Fallot. The presentation of syncope during exercise without prodrome presenting for the first time at age 44 is unlikely to be vagal mediated. While atrial flutter may occur, 1:1 conduction is not as common an explanation for syncope in these patients.
        </exp>
    <aImage>mediaSCD\Q7_ACHD algo.png</aImage>
    <ref>https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000549</ref>
</question>

</qXML>